Yes. So a friend of
mine, who has all his life been a
passionate fan
of music, and when he made some money,
he built himself a dedicated music
room with a fancy stereo, and he's
lined with CDs, and now he's going
back and
buying vinyl, and he's playing all
that.
And he decided that he was going to
learn to play the guitar.
And I was talking to him about it, and
I said, well, if you're going to learn
to play the guitar, it's a really good
idea to get lessons, because you just
go a lot faster if you get lessons.
And he said, oh, no, I don't want to
take lessons.
I was like, OK. And I said, well, why
don't you want to take lessons?
He said, because I don't want to learn
how to read music.
And this is a friend of mine who's got
PhD in chemistry, so he's not an
idiot,
although he's been quite idiotic about
this.
And I said, well, why don't you want
to learn music notation?
Yeah, well, you pick it up really
easily.
And he said, oh, yeah, but Paul
McCartney doesn't read music.
And I took about half a second, and I
said, yeah, but there's a big point
here.
You're not Paul McCartney.
You're not a genius. Paul McCartney is
literally the most successful musician
who has ever lived by a bunch of
different majors.
He's not the person you should be
comparing yourself to when you start
to learn
the guitar. Right? That is just a
recipe for misery.